Calvin Cheng

Software Developer | B. Eng Electrical Engineer

github.com/ChengCalvin
in linkedin.com/in/calvincheng95/
chengcalvin.github.io

in linkedin.com/in/calvincheng95/
calvincheng95@gmail.com

Summary

Professional Junior Engineer with a strong ability to communicate user needs into concise requirements for the engineering team and a self-taught developer with a strong ability to build Full-Stack applications.

Technical Skills

Programming Language | JavaScript (fluent) • HTML/CSS (fluent) • TypeScript (prior experience) • Java (prior experience) • Python (prior experience) • C++ (prior experience)

Stack | React/Redux • Next.js • MongoDB • Node • Express • Rest API

Applications Tools | Visual Studio Code • Git • Agile Methodology • Microsoft Office • JIRA

Educations

Concordia University | Bachelor's in Electrical Engineering Co-op | 2014 - 2018

• **Project Smart Paddling** (3rd place) | Planned milestones and drafted design requirements for Smart Paddling, facilitated workload for team to perform for the project as well as course load. Responsible for identifying the algorithm used for unit conversion to obtain desired values.

Experiences

REL Realty Advisors | Software Developer | Website: relra.com | SEPT 2020 - PRESENT

- Built and deployed on Vercel the company website using React and Next.js based on visual requirements from a graphic designer (tools: Emailjs, next-i18next).
- Created reusable and scalable React components to envision adding new dataset.
- Continuous support for refactoring and optimizing the codebase.
- Used ReCaptcha to minimize bot spam emails.

CAE Inc. | Electrical System Engineering | APR 2019 – APR 2020

• Responsible for producing Electrical System Diagrams of aircraft simulator (tools: Jira, Autocad).

Zimmer Biomet | Quality Assurance Engineering (System) | AUG 2018 – MAR 2019

- Worked directly with Product Owner, Engineers and Managers to improve engineering design documents based on User Needs; ensured technical documents and test reports meet FDA guidelines.
- Planned and Tracked my tasks using project management tool such as Kanban using agile methodology to sync with the team.

Projects

E-Sport Statistic Tracker | Website: guesswhoapp.herokuapp.com/ | APR 2020 – MAY 2020

The goal of this project was to get myself familiar with the disciplines involved with building a complete software product and learn how to build an app end-to-end.

- Designed, architected, and deployed on Heroku a web app to allow professional and casual League of Legends players to train and improve their game knowledge about team composition. The app uses React.Js, Redux, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, and Restful API calls.
- Build a user authentication system that allows users to log in and sign up on the website with user validation and verification.
- Built web crawler using Beautifulsoup Python package to store data in a MongoDB database.

Volunteer

Tutoring | SEPT 2020 – DECEMBER 2020

• Tutored a McGill student in their programming classes in Java with Object-Oriented Programming concepts.